|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| [](https://www.microsip.org/) | [microsip](https://www.microsip.org/)<br><br>[SIP softphone for Windows based on PJSIP stack](https://www.microsip.org/) |     |

Privacy Policy
==============

Privacy Policy for microsip.org  
  
The privacy of our visitors to microsip.org is important to us.  
  
At microsip.org, we recognize that privacy of your personal information is important. Here is information on what types of personal information we receive and collect when you use and visit microsip.org, and how we safeguard your information. We never sell your personal information to third parties.  
  
This Privacy Policy describes the collection and use of information on our website. Please read this policy before using, or submitting information to this site. By using this site, you signify that you agree to this Privacy Policy. Although this site contains links to other websites, please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of those, or any other, sites. If you have questions about how those websites collect and use data, you should carefully read those sites’ privacy policies.  
  
**Personal Information Collected on this Website**  
  
No personal information is collected on this website from consumers who browse for information about the softphone or download any files.  
  
The only personal information collected on this website is gathered on our "Wish List", "Contact Us" and "Custom Build" forms. In the consumer form, fields are provided so that users can submit questions or comments and provide contact information including name, email address, and phone number. We collect this personal information so that we can respond to these inquiries, comments, and questions. We do not share information submitted by consumers with other third parties. We also may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law, including by search warrant, subpoena, or court order. You do not need to disclose any personal information to Microsip in order to submit a comment or complaint. However, we may be unable to respond or take appropriate action if your information is incomplete.  
  
As discussed below, we also collect non-personally identifiable information on this website. However, we do not merge any of the personal information collected via our contact form with anonymous data collected on our website.  
  
**Non-Personally Identifiable Data Collected on this Website**  
  
We collect and store in server logs non-personally identifiable information, including but not limited to browser type, IP address, operating system, the date and time of visits, the pages visited on the site, time spent viewing the site, and return visits to the site. We also use Google Analytics, a service that records non-personally identifiable data such as browser type, operating system, the date and time of a visit, where visitors came from, the pages visited on this website, the time spent viewing site, where visitors went when they left the site, and return visits to the site.  
  
We aggregate this non-personally identifiable data to better understand how visitors use our site, and to help manage, maintain, and report on use of our website. We store IP addresses for fraud detection and prevention purposes.  
  
We may share this non-personally identifiable data with third parties for the limited purpose of reporting on use of our website, or to comply with applicable law. We also may share this data with our service providers. We do not rent, sell or share any non-personally identifiable data collected on this website with third parties for marketing purposes.  
  
**Cookies**  
  
We use cookies on this website. Cookies are small text files created by a web server, delivered through a web browser, and stored on your computer. They provide a means for websites that you visit to keep track of online patterns and preferences, as well as to identify return visitors. Cookies make the personalization of your web experiences possible, so that you do not need to re-enter your information each time you visit a website.  
  
**Third Party Content and Links**  
  
This site contains links to other websites not owned by Microsip. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of those, or any other, sites. If you have questions about how those websites collect and use data, you should carefully read those sites’ privacy policies.  
  
We use third party advertisements on microsip.org to support our site.  
  
Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on your prior visits to this website or other websites.  
Google's use of advertising cookies enables it and its partners to serve ads to users based on their visit to this site and/or other sites on the Internet.  
You may opt out of personalized advertising by visiting [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads)  
Cookies of other third-party vendors or ad networks may also be used to serve ads on this site. You may visit their websites to opt out of the use of cookies for personalized advertising (if the vendor or ad network offers this capability). Alternatively, you can opt out of some third-party vendors’ uses of cookies for personalized advertising by visiting [www.aboutads.info](https://optout.aboutads.info/).  
  
**Changes to Our Privacy Policy**  
  
As our organization, membership, and services evolve, this Privacy Policy may be revised to reflect those changes. We reserve the right to amend this Privacy Policy at any time, for any reason. Notice of such amendments will be posted as an updated Privacy Policy on this website, and an effective date will be indicated. Users are encouraged to check our site frequently to review the current Privacy Policy in effect.  
  
**Questions?**  
Please contact us with any [questions](https://www.microsip.org/contact) about this website Privacy Policy.
